A Guide to the Richmond (Va.) Civil War Centennial Committee records, circa 1956-1965
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Richmond (Va.) Civil War Centennial Committee records, circa 1956-1965
The Library of Virginia
1031064, 1031085, 1031087-1031088, 1051293-1051321
18.65 cu. ft. (33 boxes)
Richmond (Va.) Circuit Court
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items were transferred to the Library of Virginia under the accession number 27668 on December 28, 1971, from the Valentine Museum where they were stored by the city of Richmond and the Richmond (Va.) Civil War Centennial Committee on August, 17, 1971.
Historical Information
The Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee was created in 1958 as one of many local counterparts to the statewide Virginia Civil War Centennial Commission. With input from the state commission, chairman J. Ambler Johnston and his staff helped celebrate Richmond's involvement in the Civil War, 1861-1865. These celebrations included several events throughout the years of the committee's existence in addition to producing a number of publications dealing with topics specific to the Richmond area. However, institutions all over the state, as well as the country, requested these publications for their own educational uses. In 1965, the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee closed, having completed its objective of promoting Richmond's history during the Civil War years.
Scope and Content
Richmond (Va.) Civil War Centennial Committee records, circa 1956-1965, contain correspondence with the committee, including some internal correspondence; projects undertaken by the committee, including publication of Richmond City Council minutes from the war years; various publications produced by the committee and research files relating to those publications; photographs, both originals and copies from other institutions; and maps related to the Civil War. The committee project records are arranged alphabetically by the name of the project; general correspondence files are arranged alphabetically by the name of the person or institution with whom the committee is corresponding; personal correspondence with the Committee Chairman is arranged chronological.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetical and chronological.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
The city of Richmond is one of Virginia's Lost Records Localities. Additional city of Richmond Court Records may be found in the Virginia Lost Records Localities Collection at the Library of Virginia. Search the Lost Records Localities Database found at the Library of Virginia web site.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Richmond (Va.) Civil War Centennial Committee
Subjects:
Committees--Virginia--Richmond
Geographical Names:
Richmond (Va.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Richmond (Va.)--History--19th century; Richmond (Va.)--History--20th century; Virginia--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Centennial celebrations, etc.
Genre and Form Terms:
Correspondence--Virginia--Richmond; Local government records--Virginia--Richmond; Maps--Virginia--Richmond; Minute books--Virginia--Richmond; Minutes--Virginia--Richmond; Photographs--Virginia--Richmond; Project files--Virginia--Richmond
Contents List
- Minute Books and Correspondence [A], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051297)
  Minute books arranged chronologically. Correspondence arranged alphabetically.
  - Minute Book, 1959 May 22-1962 Dec. 31. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minute Book, 1963 Jan. 23-1964 July 14. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minute Book, 1964 Aug. 12-1965 Nov. 30. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence [A]. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arizona CWCC correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Australia Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Correspondence [B-Cob], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051298)
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - General Correspondence [B]. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence [B]. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bakeless. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with John Bakeless, Seymour, CT.
  - Dr. Bradley-Casemate Museum. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Correspondence with Dr. Chester D. Bradley, curator of Fort Monroe Casemate Museum.
  - Brochure Packets Mailed. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Burkart. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Correspondence with Rosamond H. Burkart, Recording Secretary of the Civil War Round Table of Northern New Jersey, Inc.
  - General Correspondence [C]. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence [C]. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chamber of Commerce-Richmond. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Coblentz. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Correspondence with Rev. David Coblentz.
- Correspondence [Com-E], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051293)
  - Our Committee. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Correspondence re: Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-includes internal correspondence.
  - Correspondence-Committee 62, circa 1960-1962. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Internal correspondence.
  - Confederate Museum Newsletter. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut Centennial Commission. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mayor Crowe. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Correspondence with Richmond Mayor Morrill M. Crowe.
  - General Correspondence [D]. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sylvia Dannett. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Correspondence with Sylvia G. L. Dannette, author and Civil War historian from Scarsdale, NY.
  - District of Columbia Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence [E]. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - England Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Primarily correspondence with The Boys and Girls of the Junior Department, Our Lady of the Assumption School, Liverpool, England and the Confederate Historical Society, London.
  - Executive Director Applications. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence [F-H], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051296)
  - General Correspondence [F]. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence [G]. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence [G]. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Georgia Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Great Books. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence [H]. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence [H]. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Henrico County and Region. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Correspondence [I-Johnston], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051295)
  - General Correspondence [I]. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Indiana Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Iowa Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence [J]. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Johnston, 1959-1960. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman, Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee.
  - Johnston, 1961. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman, Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee, 1961-Folder 1 of 2. Includes two Dictabelt recordings and possibly notes about the re-creation of Stuart's ride around McClellan
  - Johnston, 1961. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee, 1961-Folder 2 of 2.
- Correspondence [Johnston], 1962-1963. (Barcodenumber 1051294)
  - Mr. Johnston, 1962. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-Folder 1 of 4.
  - Mr. Johnston, 1962. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-Folder 2 of 4. Includes an original Civil War letter that was mailed to the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee, as well as a letter from the sender giving background about the letter.
  - Mr. Johnston, 1962. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-Folder 3 of 4.
  - Mr. Johnston, 1962. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-Folder 4 of 4.
  - : Mr. Johnston, 1963. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-Folder 1 of 3.
  - Mr. Johnston, 1963. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-Folder 2 of 3.
  - Mr. Johnston, 1963. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-Folder 3 of 3.
- Correspondence [Johnston-Mc], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051303)
  - Mr. Johnston, 1964-1965. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-Folder 1 of 2.
  - Mr. Johnston, 1964-1965.. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Correspondence with J. Ambler Johnston, Chairman Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee-Folder 2 of 2.
  - General Correspondence [K]. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Kentucky. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Correspondence from Kentucky, including the University of Kentucky and Louisville Centennial Commemoration.
  - General Correspondence [L]. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Library requests. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Requests for publications produced by the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee.
  - General Correspondence [Mc]. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Correspondence [M-New Jersey], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051299)
  - General Correspondence [M]. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence [M]. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Manarin. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with Louis Manarin, an editor for the Richmond City Council Minutes publication.
  - Maryland Hobby Club. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript Society. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Massachusetts Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Mississippi Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Col. Monoghan. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence [N]. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - New Hampshire Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - New Jersey Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Correspondence [New York-Ohio], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051300)
  - New York Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - North Carolina. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Correspondence with North Carolina Confederate Centennial Commission-Folder 1 of 3, primarily the Commission's newsletter.
  - North Carolina. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with North Carolina Confederate Centennial Commission-Folder 2 of 3, primarily the Commission's newsletter.
  - North Carolina. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Correspondence with North Carolina Confederate Centennial Commission-Folder 3 of 3, primarily the Commission's newsletter.
  - General Correspondence [O]. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ohio Historical Society. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Correspondence with the Ohio Historical Society.
  - Ohio Historical Society. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Publications from the Ohio Historical Society.
- Correspondence [Okla-R], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051301)
  - Oklahoma Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence [P]. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence [P]. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Petersburg Battlefield. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Non Project Press Releases. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Prison Round Table organized in Virginia State Penitentiary. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Publishers. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence [Q]. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence [R]. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence [R]. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Richmond Hotels, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Richmond Civil War Round Table. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Correspondence [S-U], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051302)
  - General Correspondence [S]. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence [S]. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Salvation Army. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Correspondence relating to the Salvation Army Hospital Advisory Council.
  - Mayor Sheppard, 1963. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Correspondence with Richmond Mayor Eleanor Sheppard.
  - General Correspondence [T]. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Tennessee Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence [U]. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - US National Comm.-Letters. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Correspondence with the United States National Civil War Centennial Commission.
- Correspondence [V-Z], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051308)
  - General Correspondence [V]. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence [W]. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence [W]. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - West Virginia Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Whittet and Shepperson. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Correspondence with Whittet and Shepperson, a Richmond-based publication firm.
  - Wisconsin Civil War Centennial Commission. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - VA State Comm.-Letters. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Correspondence with the Virginia Civil War Commission.
  - General Correspondence [X-Y-Z]. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Woodward, 1961. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Correspondence with Richmond Mayor Claude W. Woodward, 1961
- Committee Projects [A], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051304)
  - Air Arm of the Confederacy. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Air Arm of the Confederacy. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Air Arm [New Materials]. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Airport Brochure. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Airport. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - ATO - Alpha Tau Omega. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Archives. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Award Certificate. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Awards to Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee. (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Committee Projects [Bal], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051305)
  - Bales Reception 1961 June 26. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Reception for Richard Bales, after the performance of his musical "The Confederacy."
  - Ballet 1962 March 30. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Ballet Impromptu's "An Evening of Nineteenth Century Ballet."
  - Balloon: Program Plans. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    "Birth of American Military Aviation during the Civil War" commemorative luncheon.
  - Balloon: Invited. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Correspondence with people invited to the military aviation commemorative luncheon.
  - Balloon: Continuing Correspondence Exc. Com. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Includes correspondence regarding the ceremonies committee.
  - Balloon: Monument Plans. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Balloon: Rosendahl 1843. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Correspondence with Admiral Charles E. Rosendahl, chair of the Ceremonies Committee.
  - Balloon: Coming-Also May Need More Corres. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Correspondence with people who would be attending the military aviation commemorative luncheon.
  - Balloon: Groups and Ind. Assisting. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Correspondence with groups and individuals helping organize the military aviation commemorative luncheon-Folder 1 of 2.
  - Balloon: Groups and Ind. Assisting. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Correspondence with groups and individuals helping organize the military aviation commemorative luncheon-Folder 2 of 2.
  - Balloon: General Correspondence - Folder 1 of 2. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Balloon: General Correspondence - Folder 2 of 2. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Balloon: No. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Correspondence with people who would be unable to attend the military aviation commemorative luncheon.
- Committee Projects [Bas-City], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051309)
  - Baseball. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Project compiling list of Civil War veterans who later played professional or semi-professional baseball.
  - Bellwood Depot. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - B'nai B'rith Exhibit. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Traveling exhibit focused on Jewish Americans during the Civil War-Folder 1 of 2.
  - B'nai B'rith Exhibit. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Traveling exhibit focused on Jewish Americans during the Civil War-Folder 2 of 2.
  - Brochures. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Camp Lee Marker. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Historical marker placed at Camp Lee, later Fort Lee.
  - Chamber of Commerce Program. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Chicago Tour. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Tour of Richmond given to the Chicago Civil War Roundtable.
  - Chimborazo Research. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - City Flag-New. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Related to the adoption of a new municipal flag for the City of Richmond-Folder 1 of 2.
  - City Flag-New. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Related to the adoption of a new municipal flag for the City of Richmond-Folder 2 of 2.
- Committee Projects [Civ-Council Minutes], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051307)
  - Civil War Camps and Posts in Virginia. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Civil War Hospital Marker Program. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Civil War Period Buildings in Richmond. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Civil War Reading List. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Civil War Times Tours. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Cleveland Civil War Round Table. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Company of Military Historians. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Confederate Museum, Ruffner School. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Tour. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Council Minutes [folder 1 of 3]. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Richmond City Council Minutes, 1861-1865.
  - Council Minutes [folder 2 of 3]. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Council Minutes [folder 3 of 3]. (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Committee Projects [Council Minutes, Biographies], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051306)
  - Council Minutes-Biographical Notes [A-D]. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Richmond City Council, 1861-1865.
  - Council Minutes-Biographical Notes [E-L]. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Council Minutes-Biographical Notes [M-S]. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Council Minutes-Biographical Notes [T-Z]. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Council Minutes-Biographies-Council Members. (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Committee Projects [Council Minutes, Ordinances-Gi], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051311)
  - Council Minutes-Ordinances. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Council Minutes-Pictures. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Cub Scouts. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Cultural Programs. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Currier and Ives Exhibit. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Exhibit of Civil War prints produced by New York printers Currier and Ives; exhibit was sponsored by the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee and the Friends of the Richmond Public Library, in cooperation with Nationwide Insurance, April 1962.
  - Dance Research. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Research focused on dancing during the Civil War.
  - Directory of Officials. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Display Board Plans. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Plans for a traveling display board depicting the Civil War.
  - Distribution. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    File related to the areas of distribution for a circular produced by the Committee.
  - Evacuation Committee. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Committee focused on the evacuation of Richmond when occupied by Federal Forces, April 1864.
  - Farmville Marker. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Historical marker erected at the Prince Edward Hotel, Farmville.
  - Flag Display. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    As part of the commemoration of the centennial, businesses and other organizations were asked to display both United States and Confederate flags.
  - French Teacher Visit. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Tours organized for schoolteachers visiting from France.
  - The General. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Train taken by Union troops in 1862, leading to a locomotive chase across parts of Georgia and Tennessee. The General made a stop in Richmond during the centennial celebration-Folder 1 of 2.
  - The General. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    Train taken by Union troops in 1862, leading to a locomotive chase across parts of Georgia and Tennessee. The General made a stop in Richmond during the centennial celebration-Folder 2 of 2.
  - Gintzberger. (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Memorial program at the Hebrew Cemetery recognizing Private Henry Gintzberger, a Jewish peddler who fought with Confederate troops, whose identity was lost after he was killed in battle.
- Committee Projects [Go-Man], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051311)
  - Libby Prison - Folder 1 of 2. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Libby Prison - Folder 2 of 2. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Goddin Speech. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Adaptation of a speech by C. Hobson Goddin, May 1961.
  - Grant, Ulysses S., The Association. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Grant-1864. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - High Point College Tour. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Hill, A.P. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Hills of Richmond. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Historical Points of Interest Publication. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Describes historical points of interest in the Richmond area.
  - Information Source File. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Kilpatrick. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Correspondence with J.J. Kilpatrick, editor of Richmond News Leader.
  - Hospitals. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    Civil War-era hospitals in Richmond.
  - Manuscript Society Convention, 1961. (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Committee Projects [Map-Mon], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051313)
  - Map of Richmond, 1861-1865. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Map of Richmond-Reproduction. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Files relating to the mass production of the Richmond Civil War maps; generally materials from publishing companies.
  - Map-25 Mile Area. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Covers the 25 mile area around Richmond.
  - Meeting With Council (Richmond City Council) (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Memorabilia. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Miscellany-Facts, Data, Etc. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Includes one Dictabelt recording.
  - Miscellaneous Projects. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - "Miss Centennial" Contest, 1961. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Monumental Church of Richmond. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Monuments in Richmond. (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Committee Projects [N-Richmond Nursing], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051310)
  - Needs Further Research. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Column. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - New York Civil War Round Table Tour, 1961. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - New York Round Table Tour, 1965. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - North-South Skirmishers. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Old Market Bell. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Ordinances Adopted Pertaining to Committee Functions. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Peace Convention, 1961. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Pictures-Civil War. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Pictures-Commission. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Police Academy. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Princess Go! Go!-Princess Margaret. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Police in Minutes-Richmond City Council Minutes, 1861-1865. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Publications. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Punch Bowls. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Punch Bowls. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac. (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Richmond Defenses. (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Richmond Nursing Home Program. (Box 21, Folder 19)
- Committee Projects [Richmond One-Rotary], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051315)
  - Richmond 100 Year List. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    List of Richmond area businesses, churches, organizations, etc., formed prior to 1865.
  - Richmond Public Library. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Richmond Troops-Roster. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: General Correspondence. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: General-Charts, etc. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: Budget. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: Audience-Mrs. McCormick, Invitations and Special Guests. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: Audience [Seating and Ushers]. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: Promotion-Mr. King, Publicity. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: Poster and Folder Distribution. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: Publicity-Perkinson. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: Souvenir Program. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: Script-Banks. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags: Thank Yous. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Richmond Under Two Flags. (Box 22, Folder 15)
    Outdoor drama organized by the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee.
  - Rotary Club. (Box 22, Folder 16)
- Committee Projects [S-T], 1956-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051314)
  - School Participation in Civil War Centennial. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Signs for Walking Tour. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Singer Tours. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Tours offered in conjunction with the Singer Company's "Visit USA" program, offered to European employees of the company.
  - Soldiers and Sailors. (Box 23, Folder 4)